A Guide to the Kenneth Chorley papers FA067
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Jackson Hole, 1926-1949; 1; 10 Cubic Feet
  - Water Rights, 1935-1943 (Box 27, Folder 237)
  - Western Trips, 1931, 1934 (Box 27, Folder 238)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1926-1929, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 239)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1926-1929, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 240)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1939-1944 (Box 28, Folder 241)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1939-1944 (Box 28, Folder 242)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1939-1944 (Box 28, Folder 243)
  - Western Trips - Chorley, 1939-1944 (Box 28, Folder 244)
  - Western Trips - Chorley (Box 28, Folder 245)
    Bradbury's Accident - 1939-1940 Cheyenne Rodeo - 1939
  - Western Trips - Draper, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 246)
  - Western Trips - Kendrew, 1942-1943 (Box 28, Folder 247)
  - Western Trips - Rockefeller, David, 1936, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 248)
  - Western Trips - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1940, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 249)
  - Western Trips - Rockefeller, Laurance, 1934, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 250)
  - Western Trips - Woods and Webb, 1932-1933 (Box 28, Folder 251)
  - Withdrawal of Lands - Elk Commission, 1927-1929 (Box 29, Folder 252)
  - Withdrawal of Lands - Winter Bill, 1928-1930 (Box 29, Folder 253)
  - Withdrawal Orders, 1927-1930 (Box 29, Folder 254)
  - Woodring, 1933-1935 (Box 29, Folder 255)
  - Yellowstone National Park - Extension Bill, 1928-1929 (Box 29, Folder 256)
  - Miscellany (A-M) (Box 29, Folder 257)
    Albright Operation - 1931 Barkan - 1940 Burt, Struthers - 1945 Camp Fire Club of America - 1939 Cheyenne Chamber of Commerce Building - 1935 Colter (John) Plaque - 1937 Colton, Don B. - 1930 Cramton, Louis C. - 1929 Curtis, Lucy - 1940 Deloney, W.C. - 1933 Ditch Permit No. 4472 - 1932 Donoghue - 1933 Fabian, Harold - 1930, 1938-1941 Fires - 1931 Goe, Ben F. - 1942 Gros Ventre Flood - 1927 Harrington, Frances - 1937 Hoover, Herbert (President) - 1930 Huff (Charles W.) Memorial - 1937-1939 J.Y. Ranch - 1944 Jackson Cowboy Baseball Club - 1934 Jackson Memorial Library - 1940 Markham, Joe - 1932 McLeod, D. G. - 1945 Merced Grove - 1928 Meyersahm - 1940 Miller, Leslie A. - 1934, 1940 Moore, Charles C. - 1930 Moose - 1932 Moses, Edward P. 1934
  - Miscellany (N-W) (Box 29, Folder 258)
    National Park Service - 1944 Nielson, Wilford W. - 1934-1936 Noble, Maud - 1940 O'Mahoney, Joseph C. - 1934-1937 Resor, Stanley - 1939 Reynolds, George - 1939 Richards, H.C. - 1945 Robberies - 1932 Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Visit - 1930 Schellinger, Gerard (Reverend) - 1936-1937 Seebohm, William - 1940 Sheppard, Walter B. - 1929 Skyline Ranch - 1936-1937 Smith, Janet Rae - 1936 Storage Protection - 1932 Valley Ranch School - 1932-1933 Van Derveer, Nellie H. - 1933 Van Dusen - 1930 Weather Conditions - 1934-1936 Wilson, M. L. - 1934 Winger, Richard - 1938-1943 Winter Sports Association - 1932 Wonderful Wyoming Association - 1939 Woodring - 1939
  - Audit - Grand Teton Lodge and Transportation Company - Statistics, 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 259)
    See also Box 1, Folder 1.
  - J.Y. Ranch - Inventory, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 260)
  - Snake River Land Company - Appraisal of Properties, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 261)
  - Snake River Land Company - Chronology of Events, 1927-1932 (Box 30, Folder 262)
  - Snake River Land Company - Chronology of Events, 1927-1932 (Box 30, Folder 263)
  - Snake River Land Company - History, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 264)
    See also Box 25, Folder 218.
- Personal, 1918-1974; 2; 22 Cubic Feet
  This series consists of correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, speeches, and taped interviews relating to Chorley's interest in historic preservation; the Joint Civilian Orientation Conference at Fort Benning, Georgia; Jackson Hole; Colonial Williamsburg employee interviews; the American Commission to Preserve Abu Simbel; the Morocco Education Program; New Jersey's Governor's Mansion; the Snow King Project at Jackson Hole; and other professional and personal activities. This series also includes 55 diaries (1924-1970), and 35 scrapbooks compiled by Colonial Williamsburg staff. There is also a scrapbook on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and a scrapbook on William Lyons MacKenzie King.
  The papers in this series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Arrangement
  Persistent ID ref422 (box 11/folder 87)deleted because not used
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services / Head of Reference.
  Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (audiotapes) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
  - Articles (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Material, 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material, 1954-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committees - American Committee to Preserve Abu Simbel, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Committees - American Committee to Preserve Abu Simbel, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committees - Morocco - Educational Program, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committees - National Trust for Historic Preservation - Awards Program, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committees - Morven - New Jersey's Governor's Mansion, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - General, 1935-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - General, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Rockefeller, 1935-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Diary, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Diary, 1934-1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Diary, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Diary, 1952-March 1958 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Diary, April 1958 - October 1, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Diary, October 1, 1961 - June 1964 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Diary, July 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Diary, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Diary, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Diary, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Diary, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Jackson Hole - Snow King Project - Feasibility Study and Cost Analysis, November 1972 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Reminiscences (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Scrapbooks, 1918-1969 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Speeches - Notes and Miscellany (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Speeches, 1945-1956 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Speeches, 1957-1971 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Speeches, 1957-1971 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Speeches, 1957-1971 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Speeches - National Association of Travel Organizations, September 28, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Speeches - National Council of Churches - Task Force on Leisure, April 1967 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Speeches - New Jersey Governor's Conference on Natural Beauty, May 31, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Speeches - Portsmouth Rotary Club - Strawbery Banke, July 22, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Speeches - Preservation Society of Newport County, July 12, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Speeches - Shelburne Museum - Mr. & Mrs. J.W. Webb, May 20, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Speeches - Shelburne Museum - Mr. & Mrs. J.W. Webb, May 20, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Speeches - Trail Blazer Award - Mrs. Vanderbilt Webb, March 11, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Speeches - Wilmington Travel Forum, April 16, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Speeches - Women's Club of Milwaukee, November 19, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Speeches - Women's Club of Milwaukee, November 19, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Miscellany (Box 11, Folder 88)
    Archives Royal Dinners Copyright Renewal
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Kenneth Chorley Stories, 7" (Box 12, Folder 89)
    Staircase at Wren Bldg.; Frenchman's Map; How did you come to get a job with Mr. Rockefeller?
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - "Williamsburg Award" - Speech to Colonial Williamsburg Employees, January 1956; 7" (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Wilmington New Journal Travel Forum Address, April 16, 1958; 7" (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Trip to England and Morocco - An Address to Colonial Williamsburg Employees, April 30, 1958; 7" (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Trip to England and Morocco - An Address to Colonial Williamsburg Employees, April 30, 1958; 7" (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - "Observation Point", 7" (Box 12, Folder 94)
    Kenneth Chorley interviewed by Duncan MacDonald; broadcast March 12, 1964.
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - "Prelude to Independence" - Speech by Secretary of State Dean Rusk, 1966; 7" (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - James Arnold (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Paul Buchanan (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Gene Crane, Bookbinder (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Mr. Gott (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Michal Kipps, Printer (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Edward Riley (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Miss Shaffer (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Cassette Tape - Interview with Colonial Williamsburg Employee - Henry Striker (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Cassette Tape - Interviews - Princeton Theological Seminary - Dr. P. Brown (YSU) (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Cassette Tape - Interviews - Princeton Theological Seminary - M. Hanson (YSU) (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Cassette Tape - Interviews - Princeton Theological Seminary - Earl Soles (YSU) (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Cassette Tape - Interviews - Princeton Theological Seminary -"Freedom" (YSU) (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Interviews, April 1966; 5" (Box 12, Folder 108)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Williamsburg, Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc.
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Interviews, April 1966; 5" (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tape - Interviews, April 1966; 5" (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Scrapbook, March 1918-1928 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Scrapbook, January 1, 1931 - October 19, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Scrapbook, October 21, 1932 - May 6, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Scrapbook, May 7, 1934 - December 15, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Scrapbook, October 1934 - August 1935 (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Scrapbook, December 1934 - July 1937 (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - Scrapbook, July 1937 - October 1938 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Scrapbook, December 1938 - March 1940 (Box 13, Folder 118)
  - Scrapbook, February 1940 - May 1941 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Scrapbook, May 1941 - April 1943 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Scrapbook, January 1943 - May 1944 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Scrapbook, May 1944 - December 1945 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Scrapbook, December 1945 - May 1948 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Scrapbook, July 1948 - December 1949 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Scrapbook, February 1950 - July 1950 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Scrapbook - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Scrapbook, September 1950 - May 1951 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Scrapbook, May 1951 - December 1951 (Box 14, Folder 128)
  - Scrapbook, January 1953 - April 1953 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Scrapbook, May 1953 - September 1953 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Scrapbook, September 1953 - December 1953 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Scrapbook, January 1954 - December 1954 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Scrapbook, February 1955 - June 1957 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Scrapbook, January 1956 - May 1956 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Scrapbook, April 1956 - December 1956 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Scrapbook, February 1957 - December 1957 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Scrapbook, January 1958 - April 1958 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Scrapbook, May 1958 - January 1959 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Scrapbook, January 1959 - December 1959 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Scrapbook, January 1960 - December 1960 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Scrapbook, January 1961 - December 1961 (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - Scrapbook, February 1962 - December 1962 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Scrapbook, January 1963 - December 1963 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Scrapbook, February 1964 - December 1964 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Scrapbook, January 1965 - December 1965 (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Scrapbook, December 1965 - December 1966 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - Scrapbook - William Lyon MacKenzie King, 1874-1950 (Box 15, Folder 147)
- Colonial Williamsburg, 1953-1976; 3; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  This series contains clippings pertaining to visits to the restoration by Queen Elizabeth II of Great Britain (1957) and King Paul and Queen Fredericka of Greece (1953), and the British High Command's visit (1943).
  Persistent ID ref513 (box 1,/folder 1)deleted because not used.
  - British High Command's Visit, May 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - King and Queen of Greece Visit - Clippings, November 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Queen Mother Elizabeth (Great Britain) Visit - Clippings, November 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Queen Elizabeth II (Great Britain) Visit, October 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Queen Elizabeth II (Great Britain) Visit - Clippings, October 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "News", 1958-1976; 8 Issues (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Kenneth Chorley photographs, 1030
  Chorley, Kenneth
  - Jackson Hole - Snake River Land Company (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Jackson Hole (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - King Paul and Queen Frederika of Greece - Visit (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Negatives from Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Queen Elizabeth II of Great Britain - Visit - 1, 1957 October (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Queen Elizabeth II of Great Britain - Visit - 2, 1957 October (Box 12, Folder 116)